There really isn't a recipe. It's just a
dough. It's the rolling and the
wrinkling and the patience and the
severe, but not impossible, feeling of
broken confidence that you'll get
halfway through cuz I'm not good at
this.
We're going to make some food today and
try my best to not talk much because we
have a lot going on. We're working on a
reality show, we're working on a bunch
of show formats for the Chinese content,
building a new film studio upstairs. So,
I want to give McColley Vermouth
an easier job this week. So, we're going
to make chao shao bing. It directly
translates to saucy fragrant bing.
There's really not much history. It
showed up almost overnight in the early
2000s and became like a viral food
before viral was a concept. What it
really is is a tong mian or scorched
dough, rolled thin, wrapped up, fried
quick in a wrinkly used tissue format,
scrubbed with a very savory sauce, and
garnished heavily, [clears throat]
ridiculously, sinfully with coriander
and green onions. Enough that like when
you go out into the elevator too early
during the day after you finish doing
what you're doing, you and you see
someone in the elevator, you go, "Uh, he
knows." Like that. That's how much. All
right, cool. Let's talk you through what
I've done. I've made a dough and the
dough is a 60% hydration dough with 1
and 1/2% salt with 5 to 10% fat. The
flour is all-purpose flour. Just a mix
between bread flour and cake flour or
pastry flour if you have it. What I
usually do is three [music] parts bread
flour to one part cake flour for the
ratio that I want for this application.
Same thing as dumplings. In this mixer,
I have 700 g of my mixed flour, 420 g of
water, and 10-ish g for my 1 and 1/2% of
salt plus like 50 g of fat. Any fat of
your choice. That's the dough. The only
key technique aspect for techers is that
you want to use boiling hot water to
scorch the dough. Partially cook the
proteins as well as the starches inside
the wheat flour to create [music] a
scorched dough, which is this.
I actually recommend that you make this
dough in a food processor
and not a stand mixer. It'll come
together faster. You're not really
developing gluten, my friend. You're
just here to get a nice smooth
homogeneous mass. This is not meant to
be a very stretchy food. So, from here,
I'm remove Makuta's ring and I will
separate this now into balls. This is
500 g, this is 600 g, good enough for
me. So, I'm going to make slightly
smaller Actually, you want to just make
one big one? Jeremy, all right.
All right. They hang out here. All
right, from there you let the dough rest
after you've cleft it in twain. Now,
after the 5-minute rest, which I did not
just let you do, you pop it out on the
table and you start rolling it out. Now,
a scorched dough does not stick very
hard, as you can see. I'm doing this
without any fat or flour. Scorched
doughs, for this specific regard, are
actually very, very easy to work with.
You want to flatten your dough ball out
to about roughly 3 mm thick. So, this is
where we want to be. Yeah? So, after
you've arrived here, what we're going to
do is brush it liberally with fat. After
you've brushed with fat, what I then
like to do is add some flour on top. You
don't have to be too specific, just a
light dusting, roughly like that. And
then from there, make cuts from the edge
to about 1/3 of the way in. So, let's do
H. Now, make a mental note of which one
of these little wings is the biggest.
Start with the smallest and start
lifting them into the center.
And you have just made the laziest puff
pastry on Earth.
The concept is the same, but the
technique is not. We're going to do that
to both of these dough balls, and then
we're going to let them rest and work on
some other stuff. So, chang [snorts]
xiang bing is a viral food. It's not a
historical food, I don't think.
There's no evidence to suggest that this
is like a history tradition stretching
back thousands of years.
It's a street food. It shows up almost
all over the country, but everybody has
their own rendition of this street food.
Just like tacos or burek, it's filo
dough with spinach and cheese and butter
inside. If you're Bulgarian, you call it
banitsa. If you're Greek, you might call
it a spanakopita. But, it's essentially
the same thing. Same with this. It's
just everybody has their own name for it
and claims that they invented it, but
because it's relatively modern, it's
really hard to say. A lot of northern
people like to pretend like our diet is
meat-based, but that's not true. It's
all vegetable and wheat-based. Very
heavy on the vegetables. So, this
actually is vegan besides the fact that
I'm using animal oil. So, if you were to
just use a vegetable oil, sesame oil,
whatever oil you want that comes from a
plant, you're making a vegan dish.
Generally speaking, when you're making
flaky pastries, you want to work with a
solid fat.
So, the French use butter.
So, a lot of people say they use lard
for making Chinese style flaky pastries
is because cow fat wasn't as popular.
There wasn't cows everywhere. And also,
it tastes very particular. It's not very
desserty. Especially leaf lard that
comes around the back and also around
the kidneys, the inside.
All right. So, these are our doughs.
So, let's talk a little bit about my
sauce. It's a soy bean sauce-based sauce
seasoned heavily with spices of your
choice, then finished with a little bit
of normal soy sauce at the end let down
with water until you see the texture you
like. So, my recipe is just in some fat
goes garlic and shallot, after which I
fry it off my spice mix. And my spice
mix is the exact same one I use for
skewers, which happened last episode.
Last episode. So, go check that out if
you want to. So, after the spices go in,
the oil goes red, goes in my soybean
paste. I use huang dou jiang. Huang dou
jiang, fry it off. Let [music] it get
dark. You're actually coloring the
proteins inside the soybean sauce. After
it's the doneness you like, the
brownness you like, and the smell that
you like, let it down with water, finish
with oyster sauce, and you're good to
go. The front or back of when you put
down your oyster sauce and soy sauce,
which I also added a little bit, is not
important. This at this point is just
like making a European sauce. Fry your
flavor base, put in your liquidest
flavorings, reduce, and then add water,
further reduce, add liquid, further
reduce. And then add liquid at the end
to adjust for texture and consistency,
and you end up with this. One thing I
forgot, I add sesame seeds. A lot of
people do, not everybody. I like the
sesame seeds, so I throw them in there.
I feel like it's a missed opportunity to
not toast them off in the sauce, so I
threw sesame seeds in the sauce while I
toasted my spices. We're going to let
this dough rest. We're going to let that
sauce cook, and I am going to go to the
hardware store and pick up a longer
rolling pin.
Okay? This one's too short. Now, we're
going to talk about breaking down our
green onions and our coriander. Don't
feel the need to get these too fine. A
little bit chunky is fine, like half a
centimeter. This is enough for making
one.
Maximum one. Cuz you have to understand,
when you buy this from the street
vendor, you don't buy the whole one, cuz
it's not worth making.
All right. Now, chop is not really that
important. Go as fine as your knife or
your skills will allow. Usually, I do
the stems fine, and then the leaves less
fine.
Cool. So, we are ready. So, I have my
sauce, I have my coriander.
And I have my big counter. Where's my
big stupid stick that I just bought?
Wow. Monkey King. I love it. In China,
when you see a guy with a big stick, you
don't go, "Ah, that guy looks kind of
hard to be around." You go, "Ooh, Monkey
King." All right. So,
this is my rolling pin. And we're going
to roll like this, which is why I want
it to be extra long. So, are we ready?
Ooh.
I like how the time when I need my apron
the most, I'm not wearing one.
Honestly? No, not really. You just get
some flour on it and keep on rolling it
out till it's as [music] thin as you can
humanly make it. That's really the only
rule. So, what I like to do is make it
as long as possible in one direction and
then start rolling it in the other, like
this, to widen it out. How I saw it done
as a kid is the guy presses it into the
counter like this
and then drags his shoulder across it
like that. You know? So, you can just
shh, shh, shh, shh, shh, right? So, when
it sticks to one end, you actually want
that [music] so you can push the dough
out like this. See how one end's not
moving? And I've seen him uh
roll it from the other side as well.
It's It doesn't really matter. The The
technique is not important. Just
remember get it as thin as you can. I
have decided that I'm just going to make
one cuz I'm too lazy to make two. So,
I'm going to work on this and then put
these two together. So, essentially we
made this dough, then we took a meeting
in between, about half an hour.
See these wrinkles? Those layers? That's
exactly what you want. So, once this is
about the same size, if you want, you
shove them together or just make them
individual. It's up to you. So,
generally speaking,
like these things get rolled out till
they're about 2 m long. Now, the reason
that the stick is long, I don't know if
it's the reason, but this is what the
old man told me when I was a kid. He
also used a very long stick. I've seen
it done with shorter ones. It's not
mandatory. It's so that he has a a
ruler. So, when he goes like this, oh,
that's long enough. So, he goes as wide
as his counter and as long as his stick.
That's how he measures, which is a great
way to standardize. And the best part
about this is you don't have to roll it
very beautifully shape-wise because it's
all going to get wrinkled up in the pan.
You'll see what I mean in a second.
Like the wrinkling is the most important
part of the cooking. We're going to chop
this up again at the end anyways, so no
one's going to see how good you are at
this step. So that's about as thin as I
like to go and I don't mind it
being uneven whatsoever.
Makes no difference to me. This is fine.
From here, you want to roll this dough
up. What I recommend you do first
is there's going to be your dirty hand.
This is going to be the hand that is
dirty the whole time. Just spread it
out. It's faster than a brush. All
right. Put a little bit of grease on the
rolling pin so it doesn't
get angry on the way off.
Now we're good.
Put that in your armpit. I'm going to
put a [__] ton of fat down like that and
I'm going to wrinkle it up into the
corner like this.
Wrinkle, wrinkle, wrinkle, wrinkle,
wrinkle. The more wrinkles, the better.
Feel free to stuff this into the pan and
that's how I get 2 m into one tiny
little area. So if you have a big [__]
thing, you can get it into a small
little [__] pan. Now you want as many
contact points on your hot cooking
surface as possible and then you want to
not touch it for a while.
And once you feel the bottom going
crispy, see that color? That's the color
you want. So
it's hot. Oops. The good news is
that I also [__] up, so you don't have
to feel as bad when you do. It's still
going to be edible. If you want it to be
stretchier and more uh elastic, just use
all bread flour. And then what you do at
this point is you just start fingering
it with sauce this whole time.
Get into all the folds and you want to
shove as much sauce as you can in there
and you go
Ah.
Ah. Nice. By the way, uh keep in mind
how much fat I put on the plancha and
how it's completely bone dry now. Don't
let anybody tell you that Chinese food
is healthy. I remember I used to hear
like Westerners say that Asian food is
healthier. I just don't think so.
Hell yeah. Okay, cool.
That's all I need today.
I'm not good at this. Like this will
taste just fine, but I don't look
amazing doing this. If you search up the
videos of this one guy in Dongbei doing
this, he makes it look super easy. Nice.
You drag it out.
>> [sighs]
>> This is my first time doing this, but
I see. So, the technique is like this.
There we go. That's the effect I want.
The scalded dough is easier to roll. The
raw dough is easier to fry. It's
difficult and easy both ways. Just
depends on which one you care more
about.
So, this entire portion would cost 2
euro for all this food.
>> [laughter]
>> Do I recommend you make this at home?
Absolutely. I don't recommend you think
too hard about what the proper way of
doing it is cuz I already [__] up two
times in a row. I got better the second
time around, but it's going to be
delicious either way. Even if it looks
ugly, you're chopping it up and throwing
it in a bowl anyways. And at that point,
nobody can tell the difference if you
[__] it up. Don't get hung up on dogma
and skill just because you want tasty
food. All right. So, let's do a recap.
The dough is 60 to 65% hydration
depending on your humidity in your
environment. [music] I went 60% today.
Now, you can make a scalded dough or a
cold dough. Scalded dough will be easier
to roll, harder to fry. A raw dough will
be harder to roll, easier to fry. The
recipe for my dough is 500 g of flour,
300 g of water, 2 and 1/2 g of salt, and
30-ish g of fat. Roll it thin, and then
you can put it off to the side to let it
rest. My sauce is about 50 g of fat, 50
g of shallots, 25 g of garlic, 25 g of
sesame, roughly 100 g of soybean sauce
cooked down, at which point I then added
the barbecue powder from the previous
episode in whatever ratio you wish until
it tastes nice. A little bit of oyster
sauce and soy sauce, let it down with
water till I get the texture I like.
That's your sauce, throw it off to the
side. Chop up scallions, chop up
coriander, [__] put it off to the side
until later. Roll it as thin as you can,
roll it up onto your rolling pin, and
dangle it into a flat wide pan of your
choice with about a centimeter or 3/8 of
an inch of fat inside of it. Dangle and
fold at the same time. You want it to
scrunch up. You're going to have way
more dough than you have pan. Scrunch it
up, let it fry till you see color. Scoop
it up, flip it around. Once you fold it
over, brush the folds, and then sprinkle
as liberally or as parsimoniously as you
wish your scallion and your coriander,
at which point you can then let it color
up some more, fold it up, chop it down,
throw it into a deli tub or any take-out
container of your choice, and you have
one of the most authentic inauthentic
modern classical street foods of my
childhood growing up. Ciao ciao, baby.
All right. Talk often, talk soon. Take
care, guys. Bye-bye.